The Nice Guy
Pria Baik
THIS DRAMA SERIES IS FICTIONAL, AND THE PERSONS, PLACES, ORGANIZATIONS,
DRAMA INI ADALAH FIKSI, DAN ORANG, TEMPAT, ORGANISASI,
SETTINGS AND EVENTS DEPICTED IN THIS DRAMA SERIES HAVE BEEN FICTIONALLY CREATED
Latar dan peristiwa yang digambarkan dalam serial drama ini adalah fiksi.
CHILD ACTORS AND ANIMALS WERE FILMED IN SAFE CONDITIONS
AKTOR ANAK DAN HEWAN DIFILMKAN DALAM KONDISI AMAN
WITH THE CONSENT OF AND IN THE PRESENCE OF GUARDIANS
DENGAN PERSETUJUAN DAN DI HADIRNYA WALI
BUS TICKET
TIKET BUS
Miyoung!
Miyoung!
Seokcheol.
Seokcheol.
It's all right.
Tidak apa-apa.
Let's go.
Ayo pergi.
Get on. I'll go put the luggage in.
Ayo naik. Aku akan taruh barang bawaannya.
Oh, my goodness!
Ya ampun!
Seokcheol? Seokcheol!
Seokcheol? Seokcheol!
Seokcheol!
Seokcheol!
Seokcheol! Seokcheol!
Seokcheol! Seokcheol!
After all, I saw this coming.
Lagipula, saya sudah menduga hal ini akan terjadi.
I knew I'd hesitate
Aku tahu aku akan ragu
and end up like this.
dan berakhir seperti ini.
I wanted to become a poet.
Saya ingin menjadi seorang penyair.
I wanted to become a novelist.
Saya ingin menjadi novelis.
The Nice Guy
Pria Baik
"Your name is Rocky Flower. Rocky Flower."
"Namamu Rocky Flower. Rocky Flower."
MYOUNGSAN CITY
Kota Myoungsan
"It is the hardest flower name of all, Rocky Flower."
"Itu adalah nama bunga yang paling sulit dari semuanya, Bunga Rocky."
That was such a beautiful poem.
Itu adalah puisi yang sangat indah.
All right, who'd like to go next?
Baiklah, siapa yang ingin maju berikutnya?
"On the Way Home"
"Dalam Perjalanan Pulang"
by Park Seokcheol.
oleh Park Seokcheol.
"My slippers sink deep in the snow,
"Sandal saya tenggelam dalam salju,
"My bare feet all frozen.
"Kakiku yang telanjang membeku.
"I wonder where I am headed.
"Aku ingin tahu ke mana aku menuju.
"With my socks in my hand I wonder where I'm walking.
"Dengan kaus kaki di tanganku, aku bertanya-tanya ke mana aku berjalan.
"I step on a sharp knife
"Aku menginjak pisau tajam
"And wonder who threw it out.
"Dan bertanya-tanya siapa yang membuangnya.
"It was heated and hammered Into a beautifully sharp knife.
"Itu dipanaskan dan ditempa menjadi pisau yang sangat tajam.
"It slashes."
"Itu menebas."
"Stabs
"Tusukan
"Turns
"Berubah
"Defleshes, and kills.
"Menghancurkan daging, dan membunuh.
"Something warm touches my frozen feet.
"Sesuatu yang hangat menyentuh kakiku yang beku.
"Is it my urine or your blood?"
"Apakah itu urinku atau darahmu?"
"Blood drips from the knife.
"Darah menetes dari pisau.
"I wonder who threw it out.
"Saya ingin tahu siapa yang membuangnya.
"My slippers sink deep in the snow
"Sandalku tenggelam dalam salju
"I return home."
"Saya pulang ke rumah."
That's all.
Itu saja.
I guess it's very descriptive.
Saya kira itu sangat deskriptif.
But it's a little scary.
Tapi itu sedikit menakutkan.
Your poetic expressions seem different from those of others.
Ekspresi puitis Anda tampak berbeda dari orang lain.
How should I put it? It's raw and menacing.
Bagaimana ya menjelaskannya? Ini kasar dan mengancam.
All right, let's stop here.
Baiklah, kita berhenti di sini.
When it comes to looking at the world from a poetic point of view,
Ketika melihat dunia dari sudut pandang puitis,
there's no boundary between beauty and ugliness.
tidak ada batas antara keindahan dan keburukan.
In that sense, your poem portrays honesty and sorrow.
Dalam pengertian itu, puisi Anda menggambarkan kejujuran dan kesedihan.
And a kind of passion, as well. It's very nice.
Dan semacam gairah juga. Itu sangat menyenangkan.
Let's give him a hand.
Mari kita bantu dia.
- Thank you, sir. - Thank you.
- Terima kasih, Tuan. - Terima kasih.
Seokcheol, good job today.
Seokcheol, kerja bagus hari ini.
I really liked your poem.
Saya sungguh menyukai puisi Anda.
- Thank you. - Good-bye.
- Terima kasih. - Selamat tinggal.
Do you know what he does for a living?
Tahukah Anda apa pekerjaannya?
I'm not sure.
Saya tidak yakin.
I heard he works at a construction company.
Saya dengar dia bekerja di perusahaan konstruksi.
You really don't know?
Anda benar-benar tidak tahu?
He's a gangster.
Dia seorang gangster.
What's up?
Ada apa?
Hey, Seokcheol. Are you at home?
Hai, Seokcheol. Kamu di rumah?
Me? I came out for some work in the morning. Why?
Aku? Aku keluar untuk bekerja tadi pagi. Kenapa?
It's about your fight in Woljeong-dong.
Ini tentang pertarunganmu di Woljeong-dong.
Are you guys still stuck on that?
Apakah kalian masih bingung dengan hal itu?
Look, nothing happened that day, no one got hurt.
Lihat, tidak terjadi apa-apa hari itu, tidak ada seorang pun yang terluka.
So why can't you just let it go?
So why can't you just let it go?
Because we're the police, you punk.
Because we're the police, you punk.
I'm on my way to your house.
I'm on my way to your house.
What? Why are you coming to my house?
What? Why are you coming to my house?
Hey--
Hey--
- Listen, I need to go. - Seokcheol--
- Listen, I need to go. - Seokcheol--
- Yes, boss? - Where are you?
- Yes, boss? - Where are you?
I was out exercising. I'm going to the office now.
I was out exercising. I'm going to the office now.
I'm on my way to your house with the Chairman right now.
I'm on my way to your house with the Chairman right now.
- Meet us there, not at the office. - What? My house--
- Meet us there, not at the office. - What? My house--
I'm heading to your house with Kang Taehoon and the Chairman.
I'm heading to your house with Kang Taehoon and the Chairman.
I'll see you there.
I'll see you there.
Hello? Hello--
Hello? Hello--
You gotta be kidding me.
You gotta be kidding me.
I can't believe I'm being summoned, like I'm some misbehaving child.
I can't believe I'm being summoned, like I'm some misbehaving child.
Are we there yet?
Are we there yet?
Almost.
Almost.
BAEKMUN 1-DONG ADMINISTRATIVE WELFARE CENTER
BAEKMUN 1-DONG ADMINISTRATIVE WELFARE CENTER
Hello.
Hello.
This way, please.
This way, please.
It's so nice to meet you in person.
It's so nice to meet you in person.
Is this meeting too early for you?
Is this meeting too early for you?
No, it's all right.
No, it's all right.
How about some coffee before we get started?
How about some coffee before we get started?
Sure.
Sure.
Good job, buddy.
Good job, buddy.
It must've been hard working through the long winter.
It must've been hard working through the long winter.
Why bother wiping a dead lightbulb?
Why bother wiping a dead lightbulb?
Look at that. You're growing beautifully.
Look at that. You're growing beautifully.
All my hard work has paid off.
All my hard work has paid off.
- What is it? - Father.
- What is it? - Father.
What is this I hear about the Chairman coming to our house?
What is this I hear about the Chairman coming to our house?
Captain Jang of Myoungsan Police Station kept asking me to help mediate,
Captain Jang of Myoungsan Police Station kept asking me to help mediate,
so I asked him to come over.
so I asked him to come over.
Mediate what?
Mediate what?
I heard you guys had another fight with Taehoon and his men.
I heard you guys had another fight with Taehoon and his men.
The police received a lot of complaints about it.
The police received a lot of complaints about it.
I have to go. I'm getting another call.
I have to go. I'm getting another call.
Uh--
Uh--
Jeez.
Jeez.
I swear, this house is literally like a den of thugs.
I swear, this house is literally like a den of thugs.
Sir, do you mind looking at this video to understand the situation better?
Sir, do you mind looking at this video to understand the situation better?
It happened near a club in Woljeong-dong two days ago.
It happened near a club in Woljeong-dong two days ago.
Fortunately, a civilian called it in,
Fortunately, a civilian called it in,
and we took care of the situation before it got out of hand.
and we took care of the situation before it got out of hand.
As you already know,
As you already know,
cases related to gangsters are a headache for the police too.
cases related to gangsters are a headache for the police too.
So, we've come here today to ask you to help us reach a resolution.
So, we've come here today to ask you to help us reach a resolution.
I see.
I see.
Did any civilians get hurt?
Did any civilians get hurt?
No, sir. If that were the case, I would have arrested all these men.
No, sir. If that were the case, I would have arrested all these men.
So anyone who went to the same school as you is your senior?
So anyone who went to the same school as you is your senior?
Stand up straight. Get your hands out.
Stand up straight. Get your hands out.
Hey.
Hey.
That's enough.
That's enough.
Look at you defending your junior.
Look at you defending your junior.
Maybe you should be on the same side then.
Maybe you should be on the same side then.
Stop complicating things by choosing different sides.
Stop complicating things by choosing different sides.
Whatever. Are they all inside talking?
Whatever. Are they all inside talking?
Yeah. Come smoke with me. I have something to tell you.
Yeah. Come smoke with me. I have something to tell you.
- Do you smoke? - Yes.
- Do you smoke? - Yes.
- Don't smoke, you idiot. - Let's go.
- Jangan merokok, dasar bodoh. - Ayo pergi.
If my mom catches you smoking near the crocks, she'll kill you.
Kalau ibuku memergokimu merokok di dekat tempayan, dia akan membunuhmu.
Oh. Oh.
Oh. Oh.
Why did you bring them all here?
Mengapa kamu bawa mereka semua kesini?
The Captain told me to. I had no choice.
Kapten menyuruhku. Aku tidak punya pilihan.
This brings back old memories.
Ini membawa kembali kenangan lama.
You remember those days?
Kamu ingat hari-hari itu?
Your dream was to become a novelist, but you became a thug.
Mimpimu adalah menjadi novelis, tetapi kamu malah menjadi preman.
I used to get into fights all the time, but I'm a cop today.
Dulu aku sering berkelahi, tapi sekarang aku polisi.
Life's unpredictable, huh?
Hidup tidak dapat diprediksi, ya?
You want to switch jobs with me?
Anda ingin bertukar pekerjaan dengan saya?
It wouldn't be a fair trade.
Itu bukan perdagangan yang adil.
Anyway, have you spoken to them yet?
Ngomong-ngomong, apakah kamu sudah bicara dengan mereka?
I'm going to.
Aku akan pergi.
Just do it already.
Lakukan saja sekarang juga.
You made a decision. Don't hesitate.
Kamu sudah membuat keputusan. Jangan ragu.
I'm counting on you.
Aku mengandalkanmu.
You brats. I've known you since you were kids.
Dasar anak nakal. Aku kenal kalian sejak kecil.
I've watched you grow up.
Aku melihatmu tumbuh dewasa.
Once a family starts fighting for something,
Ketika sebuah keluarga mulai memperjuangkan sesuatu,
they fight to the death.
mereka bertarung sampai mati.
That's how it's always been.
Begitulah yang selalu terjadi.
You should be on good terms with each other, like brothers,
Kalian harus berhubungan baik satu sama lain, seperti saudara,
not cause trouble like this!
tidak menimbulkan masalah seperti ini!
The two of you,
Kalian berdua,
stand up.
berdiri.
Shake hands.
Bersalaman.
Go on.
Berlangsung.
Is it that hard for you guys to apologize?
Apakah sesulit itu bagi kalian untuk meminta maaf?
Fine then. I'll make you shake hands myself.
Baiklah. Aku akan membuatmu berjabat tangan sendiri.
Now say something nice to each other.
Sekarang katakan sesuatu yang baik satu sama lain.
Now!
Sekarang!
Sir,
Pak,
I'm sorry...
Saya minta maaf...
for the trouble I caused.
atas masalah yang aku sebabkan.
That's all right. I'm sorry too.
Tidak apa-apa. Aku juga minta maaf.
Really? But you're amazing.
Benarkah? Tapi kamu hebat.
Won't you reconsider?
Tidakkah Anda akan mempertimbangkannya kembali?
I'm sorry. I didn't expect to get so many applicants.
Maaf, saya tidak menyangka akan mendapatkan begitu banyak pelamar.
I thought it would only be a few students.
Saya pikir hanya beberapa siswa saja.
I feel uncomfortable teaching a lot of people at once.
Saya merasa tidak nyaman mengajar banyak orang sekaligus.
I guess I understand.
Saya rasa saya mengerti.
Well...
Dengan baik...
could I get your autograph?
bolehkah aku mendapatkan tanda tanganmu?
- Sorry? - I subscribe to your channel.
- Maaf? - Saya berlangganan saluran Anda.
"Little Singing Room."
"Ruang Bernyanyi Kecil."
Really?
Benar-benar?
- Here, please. - I've never met a subscriber before.
- Ini, silakan. - Saya belum pernah bertemu pelanggan sebelumnya.
- Oh, my. - I'm a big fan.
- Ya ampun. - Aku penggemar beratnya.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
KANG MIYOUNG
KANG MIYOUNG
You're right, sir.
Anda benar, Tuan.
- Go on inside. - Sir!
- Silakan masuk. - Tuan!
What took you so long?
Kenapa lama sekali?
I couldn't even wash my face.
Aku bahkan tidak bisa mencuci mukaku.
The heater broke down again.
Pemanasnya rusak lagi.
I'm going to get the whole thing fixed one day.
Aku akan memperbaiki semuanya suatu hari nanti.
- Changsoo. - How have you been, sir?
- Changsoo. - Apa kabar, Tuan?
I've been well.
Saya baik-baik saja.
I hardly see you around anymore.
Aku jarang melihatmu lagi.
Hello, sir. I'm Taehoon.
Halo, Pak. Saya Taehoon.
Right, Taehoon.
Benar, Taehoon.
Boys, come over here.
Anak-anak, kemarilah.
Hey, Daegi. Let them go.
Hei, Daegi. Lepaskan mereka.
- You come in with me. - Yes, sir.
- Silakan masuk bersama saya. - Ya, Tuan.
Don't give him a hard time.
Jangan mempersulitnya.
See you around.
Sampai jumpa.
And stop all this fighting.
Dan hentikan semua pertikaian ini.
- Good-bye, sir. - Bye.
- Selamat tinggal, Tuan. - Selamat tinggal.
Sir, may I have a cup of sweet coffee while I'm here?
Tuan, bolehkah saya minum secangkir kopi manis selagi saya di sini?
Good-bye, sir. I'll see you at the office.
Selamat tinggal, Pak. Sampai jumpa di kantor.
Must be tough for you, huh?
Pasti sulit bagimu, ya?
Damn it.
Brengsek.
- Uncle! - Hey, Hyeonggeun!
- Paman! - Hei, Hyeonggeun!
Where'd you go this morning?
Ke mana kamu pergi pagi ini?
I went to draw at Daegyun's.
Saya pergi menggambar di Daegyun.
Good job.
Kerja bagus.
How diligent. You're my role model. Go on inside.
Rajin sekali. Kamu panutanku. Masuklah.
Don't run.
Jangan lari.
- I'm home. - Hi.
- Saya pulang. - Hai.
- Go wash your hands. - Okay.
- Cuci tanganmu. - Oke.
- Hey, help me with these. - What is that?
- Hei, bantu aku dengan ini. - Apa itu?
They're so heavy.
Mereka sangat berat.
It's kimchi. One for your sister, and one for Kihong.
Ini kimchi. Satu untuk adikmu, dan satu untuk Kihong.
Just send one big portion to Seokhee. Why a separate one for him?
Kirim satu porsi besar saja untuk Seokhee. Kenapa harus satu porsi terpisah untuknya?
This won't make them come over and announce their marriage.
Ini tidak akan membuat mereka datang dan mengumumkan pernikahan mereka.
Stop talking so much and just do as I say.
Berhentilah bicara terlalu banyak dan lakukan saja apa yang aku katakan.
Yes, ma'am. Roger that.
Ya, Bu. Diterima.
God, these are heavy!
Ya Tuhan, ini berat sekali!
How much do they weigh?
Berapa beratnya?
Listen, how's the search for your older sister coming along?
Dengar, bagaimana pencarian kakak perempuanmu?
I've asked some of my acquaintances, but it's gonna take a while.
Aku sudah bertanya pada beberapa kenalanku, tapi sepertinya butuh waktu.
That stupid girl.
Gadis bodoh itu.
I get that she went into hiding for what she did,
Aku mengerti dia bersembunyi atas apa yang dia lakukan,
but she should at least be worried about her son.
tetapi dia setidaknya harus khawatir tentang putranya.
Not even a phone call from her.
Bahkan tidak ada panggilan telepon darinya.
She must be too ashamed to call.
Dia pasti terlalu malu untuk menelepon.
Look at this.
Lihat ini.
It's a reminder from the bank.
Itu pengingat dari bank.
They even called two days ago.
Mereka bahkan menelepon dua hari yang lalu.
A reminder?
Sebuah pengingat?
368 million won?
368 juta won?
What a mess you've left us in, Seokkyung.
Betapa kacaunya keadaan kita, Seokkyung.
Thanks to her, we might end up going broke.
Berkat dia, kita mungkin akan bangkrut.
Who answered the call from the bank?
Siapa yang menjawab panggilan dari bank?
Instant coffee is the best. It's nice and sweet.
Kopi instan memang yang terbaik. Enak dan manis.
Father, did you talk to the guys from the bank?
Ayah, apakah Ayah sudah bicara dengan orang dari bank?
I'll handle that myself. You stay out of it.
Aku akan urus sendiri. Jangan ikut campur.
You know I can't do that.
Kau tahu aku tidak bisa melakukan itu.
And how would you possibly handle it?
Dan bagaimana Anda mengatasinya?
You know that junior of mine named Tick?
Kau tahu adik kelasku yang bernama Tick?
Yes, the loan shark, right?
Ya, rentenir, kan?
Yes. He's got a lot of connections.
Ya. Dia punya banyak koneksi.
He knows a lot of people in banks.
Dia kenal banyak orang di bank.
I'm going to go with Stick and talk to the branch manager in person.
Saya akan pergi dengan Stick dan berbicara dengan manajer cabang secara langsung.
Seokcheol, your father and I will take care of it. Don't worry.
Seokcheol, ayahmu dan aku akan mengurusnya. Jangan khawatir.
Look, you can't just go threaten a branch manager these days.
Lihat, Anda tidak bisa begitu saja mengancam manajer cabang saat ini.
You could get in serious trouble.
Anda bisa mendapat masalah serius.
They'll think you're robbers.
Mereka akan mengira kalian perampok.
I'm not going to threaten anyone.
Saya tidak akan mengancam siapa pun.
I'm going to ask them if they can extend the deadline for the payment.
Saya akan bertanya apakah mereka dapat memperpanjang batas waktu pembayaran.
I'll take care of it. Now, go away.
Aku akan mengurusnya. Sekarang, pergilah.
It's all right.
Tidak apa-apa.
Fine.
Bagus.
Bye.
Selamat tinggal.
SEOKHEE
SEOKHEE
- I heard you have Mom's kimchi for me? - Yeah.
- Kudengar kau punya kimchi buatan Ibu untukku? - Ya.
And there's one for Kihong too?
Dan ada satu untuk Kihong juga?
Bring it over to my house.
Bawalah ke rumahku.
Hey, I'm not your kimchi deliveryman.
Hei, aku bukan pengantar kimchimu.
- I'll swing by the hospital. Come take-- - I've told you not to come here.
- Aku akan mampir ke rumah sakit. Ayo bawa-- - Sudah kubilang jangan ke sini.
Just drop it off at my place. Bye.
Serahkan saja ke tempatku. Sampai jumpa.
I'm--
Aku--
Hello? Hey, Seokhee. Hey!
Halo? Hai, Seokhee. Hai!
What a brat!
Dasar anak nakal!
As if I'd let him bring the kimchi here!
Mana mungkin aku membiarkan dia membawa kimchi ke sini!
Was that Seokcheol? What was it about?
Apa itu Seokcheol? Tentang apa?
My mom's sending some kimchi for us.
Ibu saya mengirimkan kimchi untuk kita.
He wanted to drop it off here.
Dia ingin menaruhnya di sini.
You should've let him. I'd finally be able to see my friend.
Seharusnya kau membiarkannya. Akhirnya aku bisa bertemu temanku.
Are you guys really friends?
Apakah kalian benar-benar berteman?
I like everything about you except the fact that you're his friend.
Aku suka segalanya tentangmu, kecuali kenyataan bahwa kau temannya.
Honey, why do you like my brother? Other than the fact that you're friends.
Sayang, kenapa kamu suka sama adikku? Selain karena kalian berteman.
If not for him, I probably wouldn't have gone to med school.
Kalau bukan karena dia, mungkin aku tidak akan masuk sekolah kedokteran.
Back in school, I got bullied a lot because I was a small kid.
Dulu sewaktu sekolah, saya sering diganggu karena saya masih kecil.
Seokcheol would beat up the bullies and tell them not to mess with his friend.
Seokcheol akan memukuli para pengganggu dan memberi tahu mereka agar tidak mengganggu temannya.
Thanks to that, I studied hard and became a doctor.
Berkat itu, saya belajar giat dan menjadi dokter.
What about Byeongsoo?
Bagaimana dengan Byeongsoo?
Byeongsoo? He was a total loser in school.
Byeongsoo? Dia benar-benar pecundang di sekolah.
I can't believe he's running around trying to catch criminals these days.
Aku tak percaya dia berkeliaran mencoba menangkap penjahat akhir-akhir ini.
What are you doing after work?
Apa yang kamu lakukan setelah bekerja?
Maybe I could come over to your place, and we could have some wine?
Mungkin aku bisa datang ke tempatmu, dan kita bisa minum anggur?
I have plans with a friend this evening.
Saya ada rencana dengan seorang teman malam ini.
That's okay. I'll just wait for you at your place.
Tidak apa-apa. Aku akan menunggumu di rumahmu saja.
Okay? Text me on your way back.
Oke? Kirim pesan padaku saat kamu dalam perjalanan pulang.
- Don't take off your socks at my house. - Okay.
- Jangan lepas kaus kakimu di rumahku. - Oke.
MYOUNGSAN INDUSTRIES
INDUSTRI MYOUNGSAN
What?
Apa?
What did you just say?
Apa yang barusan kamu katakan?
I want to quit.
Saya ingin berhenti.
What are you talking about all of a sudden?
Apa yang tiba-tiba kamu bicarakan ?
It isn't sudden.
Itu tidak tiba-tiba.
I've been thinking about it for a while now.
Saya sudah memikirkannya beberapa waktu lalu.
I just didn't tell you.
Aku hanya tidak memberitahumu.
What on earth are you saying?
Apa sebenarnya yang kamu katakan?
Hey, this isn't like any ordinary job. You can't just quit when you want to.
Hei, ini bukan pekerjaan biasa. Kamu tidak bisa berhenti begitu saja kalau mau.
Then,
Kemudian,
what should I do?
apa yang harus saya lakukan?
You want me to turn into Taehoon?
Kau ingin aku berubah menjadi Taehoon?
Listen, boss, I'm sorry to have to say this,
Dengar, bos, saya minta maaf harus mengatakan ini,
but I don't intend to be mistreated like that.
tetapi saya tidak ingin diperlakukan buruk seperti itu.
Come on, man.
Ayolah, kawan.
What's wrong with you?
Ada apa denganmu?
You know I have a lot of respect for you.
Kau tahu, aku sangat menghormatimu.
You're younger than me, but I respect you despite that.
Kamu lebih muda dariku, tapi aku menghormatimu meski begitu.
It's true, you punk.
Benar, dasar berandalan.
It's just that your timing's all wrong.
Hanya saja waktumu salah.
The Chairman's already on edge because of that bastard Taehoon.
Ketua sudah gelisah karena si bajingan Taehoon.
If I go up to him and say, "Boss, Seokcheol wants to quit his job,"
Jika aku menghampirinya dan berkata, "Bos, Seokcheol ingin berhenti dari pekerjaannya,"
what do you think he'll say?
Menurutmu apa yang akan dia katakan?
There's no way I can tell him that.
Tidak mungkin aku bisa mengatakan hal itu padanya.
- Okay, then I'll tell him myself. - Hey!
- Baiklah, kalau begitu aku sendiri yang akan memberitahunya. - Hei!
Sit down.
Duduk.
Sit back down, come on.
Ayo, duduk kembali.
Let's talk about it.
Mari kita bicarakan hal ini.
This is exhausting.
Ini melelahkan.
I've got it.
Aku sudah mendapatkannya.
Take care of that matter with the third district first.
Selesaikan masalah itu dengan distrik ketiga terlebih dahulu.
Once you do, I'll tell the Chairman that we should let you go.
Kalau begitu, aku akan bilang pada Ketua bahwa kita harus melepaskanmu.
It's more likely he'll approve your resignation then.
Kemungkinan besar dia akan menyetujui pengunduran diri Anda saat itu.
Even if he doesn't,
Bahkan jika dia tidak melakukannya,
I'll do everything I can to help you leave.
Aku akan melakukan apa saja untuk membantumu pergi.
You know it's always good to end something on a positive note.
Anda tahu selalu baik untuk mengakhiri sesuatu dengan catatan positif.
Take care of the third district,
Jaga distrik ketiga,
get an incentive by securing the construction deal,
mendapatkan insentif dengan mengamankan kesepakatan konstruksi,
take your severance pay, and then you can be on your way.
ambil pesangonmu, lalu kamu bisa melanjutkan perjalananmu.
What do you say? Okay?
Apa katamu? Oke?
Come on, dude, you need money to start a new life.
Ayolah, Bung, kamu butuh uang untuk memulai hidup baru.
If you leave empty-handed, you'll just ruin your chances out there.
Jika Anda pulang dengan tangan kosong, Anda hanya akan menghancurkan kesempatan Anda di luar sana.
This deal will be my last job. Okay?
Kesepakatan ini akan menjadi pekerjaan terakhirku. Oke?
Absolutely. I won't stop you.
Tentu saja. Aku tidak akan menghentikanmu.
Okay. I'll make sure to settle the deal.
Oke. Aku akan pastikan untuk menyelesaikan kesepakatannya.
- On one condition. - What is it?
- Dengan satu syarat. - Apa itu?
I won't resort to any violence.
Saya tidak akan melakukan kekerasan.
Everything will work out if we just go with the flow.
Segala sesuatu akan berjalan baik jika kita mengikuti arus saja.
All right, fine.
Baiklah, baiklah.
Fine, I get it.
Baiklah, saya mengerti.
That's not how gangsters work, you bastard.
Bukan begitu cara gangster bekerja, dasar bajingan.
God, you're driving me nuts.
Ya Tuhan, kau membuatku gila.
Hello?
Halo?
What? Why did you bring it here? I told you to drop it off at the house!
Apa? Kenapa kamu bawa ke sini? Sudah kubilang untuk menitipkannya di rumah!
I'm already here.
Aku sudah di sini.
Meet me at the information desk.
Temui saya di meja informasi.
My car reeks of kimchi. I can't stand it.
Mobilku bau kimchi. Aku tidak tahan.
Hey, just put it in your car.
Hei, taruh saja di mobilmu.
Then my car's gonna smell too.
Nanti mobilku juga bau.
Well, it's your kimchi, after all.
Ya, itu kimchi milikmu.
Oh, come on. I'm meeting a friend today.
Oh, ayolah. Aku akan bertemu teman hari ini.
I can't drive around with kimchi in my car.
Aku tidak bisa bepergian dengan kimchi di mobilku.
Your friend can help you carry it.
Teman Anda dapat membantu Anda membawanya.
- Who's the friend, by the way? - It's no one you know.
- Ngomong-ngomong, siapa temannya? - Bukan seseorang yang kau kenal.
Fine, whatever.
Baiklah, terserah.
Come down and take your kimchi, or I'll leave it here. Bye.
Turunlah dan ambil kimchi-mu, atau aku tinggalkan di sini. Sampai jumpa.
These women have reduced me to a kimchi deliveryman.
Para wanita ini telah merendahkan saya menjadi seorang pengantar kimchi.
Yeah, I'm just walking in now.
Ya, saya baru saja masuk sekarang.
Where are you?
Kamu ada di mana?
Me?
Aku?
I'm at...
Saya di...
Seokcheol?
Seokcheol?
Long time no see.
Lama tak jumpa.
Yeah...
Ya...
Ernest Hemingway once said,
Ernest Hemingway pernah berkata,
"The sun also rises,
“Matahari juga terbit,
"and as long as the sun rises, there's hope."
"dan selama matahari terbit, masih ada harapan."
My sun has risen again.
Matahariku telah terbit lagi.
Do you two know each other?
Apakah kalian berdua saling kenal?
Us? We--
Kita? Kita--
We don't. We just ran into each other a few times.
Tidak. Kami hanya bertemu beberapa kali.
Yeah, you transferred so suddenly in ninth grade.
Ya, kamu pindah secara tiba-tiba saat kelas sembilan.
You must not know each other.
Kalian pasti tidak saling mengenal.
Kang Miyoung, this is my brother, Park Seokcheol.
Kang Miyoung, ini saudaraku, Park Seokcheol.
Hello, Seokcheol.
Halo, Seokcheol.
Hi.
Hai.
I recently moved back to this neighborhood with my mom.
Saya baru saja pindah kembali ke lingkungan ini bersama ibu saya.
I see.
Jadi begitu.
So, how's life?
Jadi, bagaimana kehidupan?
She's pretty famous, you know?
Dia cukup terkenal, tahu?
- She is? - Yeah, she's really good at singing.
- Benar kan? - Ya, dia jago banget nyanyinya.
People from other colleges would come to hear her sing at college festivals.
Orang-orang dari perguruan tinggi lain akan datang untuk mendengarkannya bernyanyi di festival perguruan tinggi.
I thought she'd become a pop star, but oddly enough, she didn't.
Saya pikir dia akan menjadi bintang pop, tetapi anehnya, dia tidak menjadi bintang.
I'm not so good at all the dancing.
Aku tidak pandai menari.
I have two left feet.
Saya punya dua kaki kiri.
You sure seem a bit stiff.
Kamu tampaknya agak kaku.
- My body can't keep up. - Look. This is her channel.
- Tubuhku tak sanggup lagi. - Lihat. Ini salurannya.
Hey!
Hai!
"Little Singing Room."
"Ruang Bernyanyi Kecil."
She's got a thousand subscribers.
Dia punya seribu pelanggan.
She's a celebrity.
Dia seorang selebriti.
It's 900-something. I haven't hit 1,000 yet.
Sudah 900-an. Aku belum mencapai 1.000.
956 is almost as good as 1,000.
956 hampir sama baiknya dengan 1.000.
- Yeah. - This is amazing.
- Ya. - Ini menakjubkan.
Hey, you haven't liked her posts.
Hei, Anda tidak menyukai postingannya.
She's your friend. Show her some support, you brat.
Dia temanmu. Dukung dia, dasar bocah nakal.
An agency's reached out to her after watching her videos.
Sebuah agensi menghubunginya setelah menonton videonya.
- They asked her to audition for them. - Whoa.
- Mereka memintanya untuk mengikuti audisi untuk mereka. - Wah.
I'm so nervous about it.
Saya sangat gugup karenanya.
There's no need to be nervous.
Tidak perlu gugup.
I'm sure you'll do great. Good luck.
Saya yakin kamu akan hebat. Semoga berhasil.
Thanks. I'll do my best.
Terima kasih. Saya akan berusaha sebaik mungkin.
What's going on here?
Apa yang terjadi di sini?
What do you mean? I'm just showing your friend some support.
Apa maksudmu? Aku cuma menunjukkan dukungan pada temanmu.
JUST AS IT WAS BY YOO JAEHA
SEPERTI YANG DIMILIKI OLEH YOO JAEHA
♪ The old days will never come back ♪
??? Masa lalu takkan pernah kembali???
♪ I'll cherish those memories ♪
??? Aku akan menghargai kenangan itu???
♪ I'll embrace that sense of longing ♪
??? Akankah kudekap rasa rindu itu???
♪ Those days have passed ♪
??? Hari-hari itu telah berlalu ???
♪ But the memories are unforgettable ♪
??? Tapi kenangannya gak terlupakan???
♪ Let's shine a light on the future ♪
??? Mari kita soroti masa depan ???
♪ The memories of the old days ♪
??? Kenangan masa lalu???
♪ Come back fresher each day ♪
??? Kembali lebih segar setiap hari ???
Seokcheol, close your eyes.
Seokcheol, tutup matamu.
Why?
Mengapa?
Close your eyes and focus on listening this time.
Tutup mata Anda dan fokuslah mendengarkan kali ini.
Okay.
Oke.
I have a crush on you.
Aku jatuh cinta padamu.
You said you liked reading books.
Kamu bilang kamu suka membaca buku.
I haven't read it myself.
Saya sendiri belum membacanya.
I thought this had the best title of all.
Menurutku, ini judul yang terbaik.
"The Sun Also Rises."
"Matahari Juga Terbit."
I figured you didn't like me back.
Aku pikir kau juga tidak menyukaiku.
It's all right. I didn't get my hopes up.
Tidak apa-apa. Aku tidak terlalu berharap.
There are a lot of pretty girls in high school--
Ada banyak gadis cantik di sekolah menengah--
I like you.
Aku menyukaimu.
I've had...
Saya sudah punya...
a crush on you too.
juga naksir kamu.
Miyoung!
Miyoung!
What a beautiful view! Aren't you glad we came here?
Pemandangan yang indah sekali! Senang sekali kita datang ke sini, ya?
THE SUN ALSO RISES
MATAHARI JUGA TERBIT
TO SEOKCHEOL FROM M.Y.
UNTUK SEOKCHEOL DARI SAYA
Uncle, could I sleep in here with you?
Paman, bolehkah aku tidur di sini bersamamu?
Grandpa had a drink, and now he's snoring loudly.
Kakek minum, dan sekarang dia mendengkur keras.
Sure, come in.
Tentu, silakan masuk.
There you go.
Itu dia.
Hyeonggeun.
Hyeonggeun.
What do you think? Isn't she good?
Bagaimana menurutmu? Bukankah dia baik?
I don't know.
Aku tidak tahu.
What do you mean? Watch closely.
Apa maksudmu? Perhatikan baik-baik.
She's a good singer and she's pretty.
Dia penyanyi yang bagus dan dia cantik.
Yes, but my mom's prettier.
Ya, tapi ibuku lebih cantik.
What are you talking about? She's way prettier than your mom.
Apa yang kamu bicarakan? Dia jauh lebih cantik daripada ibumu.
I don't think so.
Saya kira tidak demikian.
- Go sleep with Grandpa. - No, I agree. She's prettier.
- Tidurlah dengan Kakek. - Tidak, aku setuju. Dia lebih cantik.
There you go. You should always tell the truth.
Begitulah. Kamu harus selalu mengatakan yang sebenarnya.
- Uncle. - Yes?
- Paman. - Ya?
Haven't you found my mom yet?
Kamu belum menemukan ibuku?
Do you miss her a lot?
Apakah kamu sangat merindukannya?
Yes.
Ya.
But not a lot. Just a little.
Tapi tidak banyak. Hanya sedikit.
Be patient, buddy.
Sabar ya, sobat.
I'll find your mom and bring her home.
Aku akan menemukan ibumu dan membawanya pulang.
Grandma said Mom's too scared of Grandpa to come home.
Nenek berkata Ibu terlalu takut pada Kakek untuk pulang.
Because if she gets caught, he'll break her legs.
Karena jika dia tertangkap, dia akan mematahkan kakinya.
No, I'm sure he didn't mean it.
Tidak, saya yakin dia tidak bermaksud begitu.
He wouldn't do that.
Dia tidak akan melakukan itu.
Now try and get some sleep.
Sekarang cobalah tidur.
I'll turn the lights off.
Aku akan mematikan lampunya.
Hello, my name is Kang Miyoung.
Halo, nama saya Kang Miyoung.
I prefer singing my own compositions.
Saya lebih suka menyanyikan komposisi saya sendiri.
I want to be a singer-songwriter someday.
Saya ingin menjadi penyanyi-penulis lagu suatu hari nanti.
Today I'm going to sing you a cover song I posted online.
Hari ini saya akan menyanyikan sebuah lagu cover yang saya posting online.
Come on.
Ayo.
YOU CAN DO IT, CHEER UP!
KAMU BISA, TETAP SEMANGAT!
Here's 300,000 won.
Ini 300.000 won.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
Life is hard, isn't it?
Hidup itu sulit, bukan?
Every month, I send 500,000 won out of my paycheck to my family,
Setiap bulan, saya mengirimkan 500.000 won dari gaji saya untuk keluarga saya,
I pay their utility bills,
Saya membayar tagihan listrik mereka,
and pay my own rent too.
dan membayar sewa saya sendiri juga.
If I want to buy myself a new outfit, I need to save up for a whole year.
Jika saya ingin membeli baju baru, saya perlu menabung untuk setahun penuh.
Fortunately, people are clueless about it.
Untungnya, orang-orang tidak tahu menahu tentang hal itu.
Thanks to our good looks.
Berkat ketampanan kita.
So what if our clothes are cheap? Our pretty faces make up for it.
Jadi kenapa kalau baju kita murah? Wajah cantik kita bisa menebusnya.
I'll pay you back soon.
Aku akan segera membayarmu kembali.
That's okay. Take your time.
Tak apa. Santai saja.
Good luck with your audition tomorrow.
Semoga sukses dengan audisinya besok.
Let's eat.
Ayo makan.
We rarely offer such an opportunity, but we've seen your potential.
Kami jarang menawarkan kesempatan seperti itu, tetapi kami telah melihat potensi Anda.
Please relax, and take your time.
Tenang saja, dan luangkan waktu Anda.
Okay, thank you.
Oke, terima kasih.
- Are you ready? - Yes.
- Apakah kamu siap? - Ya.
Let's begin.
Mari kita mulai.
Oh. Check out her singing. She's great.
Oh. Coba lihat nyanyiannya. Dia hebat.
- She is? - Really?
- Dia? - Benarkah?
♪ I write ♪
??? Saya menulis ???
So, you're telling me you can't sing in front of people?
Jadi, kau bilang kau tidak bisa bernyanyi di depan orang lain?
Yes.
Ya.
You need to have courage to be a singer.
Anda harus memiliki keberanian untuk menjadi seorang penyanyi.
You can't shy away from people.
Anda tidak bisa menghindar dari orang lain.
I'm sorry. I'll try and work on it.
Maaf. Saya akan coba memperbaikinya.
Everyone in this industry works hard.
Semua orang di industri ini bekerja keras.
They do their best.
Mereka melakukan yang terbaik.
But they're not always willing to wait.
Namun mereka tidak selalu mau menunggu.
Anyway, thanks for coming in.
Bagaimana pun, terima kasih sudah datang.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
MYOUNGSAN HOSPITAL
RUMAH SAKIT MYOUNGSAN
What is it?
Apa itu?
Spit it out.
Katakan saja.
You know...
Kamu tahu...
From the other day...
Dari beberapa hari yang lalu...
That friend of yours...
Temanmu itu...
Miyoung...
Miyoung...
What about her?
Bagaimana dengan dia?
You came here to ask me for her number?
Kau datang ke sini untuk meminta nomor teleponnya?
What?
Apa?
How did you know? Did you read my mind?
Kok kamu tahu? Kamu baca pikiranku?
How very interesting.
Sangat menarik.
Miyoung asked me for your number too.
Miyoung juga meminta nomor teleponmu.
Really?
Benar-benar?
Well, did you give her my number?
Baiklah, apakah kamu memberinya nomor teleponku?
Do you have feelings for her? Be honest.
Apa kamu punya perasaan padanya? Jujur saja.
Why? Is it wrong to have feelings for her?
Kenapa? Apakah salah memiliki perasaan padanya?
Miyoung's my friend, I care about her. And she's had a tough life.
Miyoung temanku, aku peduli padanya. Dan dia punya kehidupan yang sulit.
She asked to meet me because she wanted to borrow money.
Dia meminta untuk bertemu dengan saya karena dia ingin meminjam uang.
Borrow money?
Meminjam uang?
Is her family struggling?
Apakah keluarganya sedang berjuang?
Kind of, but it's amazing how well she's dealing with it.
Ya, tapi sungguh menakjubkan betapa baiknya dia mengatasinya.
So, did you lend her the money?
Jadi, apakah Anda meminjaminya uang?
Yeah, I lent her 300,000 won.
Ya, saya meminjamkannya 300.000 won.
I know about her situation, so I couldn't say no.
Saya tahu tentang situasinya, jadi saya tidak bisa mengatakan tidak.
Good job, little sister.
Kerja bagus, adik kecil.
What is her situation, though?
Bagaimana situasinya?
That's none of your business.
Itu bukan urusanmu.
She's had terrible luck, not to mention that sudden transfer.
Dia mengalami nasib sial, belum lagi pemindahan mendadak itu.
There were weird rumors about her in school.
Ada rumor aneh tentangnya di sekolah.
What rumors?
Rumor apa?
All you need to know is that something bad happened.
Yang perlu Anda ketahui adalah sesuatu yang buruk telah terjadi.
I'm busy. Bye.
Aku sibuk. Sampai jumpa.
Hey, wait. Did you give her my number?
Hei, tunggu. Kamu sudah memberikan nomorku padanya?
Hey, tell me before...
Hei, ceritakan padaku sebelumnya...
That brat.
Anak nakal itu.
Hi, Seokcheol. This is Miyoung.
Hai, Seokcheol. Ini Miyoung.
It was nice to meet you. But we didn't get to catch up properly.
Senang bertemu denganmu. Tapi kita belum sempat bertemu dengan baik.
Hi.
Hai.
It was nice meeting you too.
Senang bertemu dengan Anda juga.
- Shall we meet today? - Would you like to meet?
- Bagaimana kalau kita bertemu hari ini? - Apakah kamu ingin bertemu?
- Enjoy your drink. - Thank you.
- Nikmati minuman Anda. - Terima kasih.
- Would you like to order? - What?
- Apakah Anda ingin memesan? - Apa?
Oh?
Oh?
Do you work here?
Apakah Anda bekerja di sini?
You look good.
Kamu terlihat baik.
You too.
Kamu juga.
You've somehow gotten cooler over the years.
Entah bagaimana, kamu jadi semakin keren dari tahun ke tahun.
- Come on, don't tease me. - Really.
- Sudahlah, jangan goda aku. - Sungguh.
I'm sorry.
Saya minta maaf.
For leaving without telling you.
Karena pergi tanpa memberitahumu.
I always regretted it.
Saya selalu menyesalinya.
I shouldn't have done that.
Aku seharusnya tidak melakukan itu.
Well, it's all in the past now.
Ya, itu semua sudah berlalu sekarang.
I figured you must have had your reasons.
Aku pikir, kamu pasti punya alasan.
I see.
Jadi begitu.
Despite what happened, I thought about you a lot.
Meski apa pun yang terjadi, aku banyak memikirkanmu.
I would wonder how you were doing,
Aku ingin tahu bagaimana kabarmu,
and whether we'd ever get to meet again.
dan apakah kita akan bertemu lagi.
I actually thought about you...
Aku benar-benar memikirkanmu...
a lot too.
banyak juga.
I would wonder how you were, if you were doing what you wanted,
Aku ingin tahu bagaimana kabarmu, jika kamu melakukan apa yang kamu inginkan,
and if we'd ever get to meet again, even once, you know.
dan jika kita bisa bertemu lagi, meski hanya sekali, kau tahu.
I am doing what I want in life.
Saya melakukan apa yang saya inginkan dalam hidup.
It's just not working out well.
Itu tidak berjalan dengan baik.
Oh, wait. How did the audition go?
Oh, tunggu dulu. Bagaimana audisinya?
Uh...
Eh...
I didn't make it.
Saya tidak berhasil.
Huh? Really? Why?
Hah? Benarkah? Kenapa?
Goodness.
Kebaikan.
The truth is, I can't sing in front of people.
Sebenarnya, saya tidak bisa bernyanyi di depan orang banyak.
When someone's watching me...
Ketika seseorang memperhatikanku...
I panic and find it hard to breathe.
Saya panik dan sulit bernapas.
I'm too shy. It's like a disease, you know.
Aku terlalu pemalu. Itu seperti penyakit, lho.
I can sing just fine when I'm alone, but strangely...
Saya bisa bernyanyi dengan baik saat sendirian, tetapi anehnya...
I think it's better when I play the piano, though.
Saya pikir lebih baik kalau saya memainkan piano.
It eases my mind.
Itu menenangkan pikiranku.
It's okay. Happens to me all the time.
Nggak apa-apa. Sering terjadi padaku.
Oh.
Oh.
I better get going. I'll miss the bus.
Sebaiknya aku pergi. Nanti aku ketinggalan bus.
Where are you going? Let me drive you.
Kamu mau ke mana? Biar aku yang antar.
Oh, just the bus stop.
Oh, hanya halte bus.
It's okay. I'm old enough to drive now.
Nggak apa-apa. Aku sudah cukup umur untuk menyetir sekarang.
- Let me drive you. - It's far.
- Biar aku yang mengantarmu. - Jauh.
- No problem. - You sure? It's very far.
- Tidak masalah. - Yakin? Jauh sekali.
What is it?
Apa itu?
I always take the bus,
Saya selalu naik bus,
so you driving me today makes it feel like a road trip.
jadi kamu yang mengantarku hari ini membuatku merasa seperti melakukan perjalanan darat.
I love it.
Saya menyukainya.
Me too.
Saya juga.
I'm mostly driving by myself,
Saya sering menyetir sendiri,
so it's nice to be with someone.
jadi senang rasanya bersama seseorang.
Shall we carpool from now on?
Apakah kita akan naik mobil bersama mulai sekarang?
A nursing home?
Panti jompo?
I come here to visit my mom.
Saya datang ke sini untuk mengunjungi ibu saya.
You remember my mom, right?
Kamu ingat ibuku, kan?
Of course. Does she live here?
Tentu saja. Apakah dia tinggal di sini?
She's unwell, so I had to put her up here.
Dia sedang tidak sehat, jadi saya harus membawanya ke sini.
Do you mind if I come with you? I'd like to say hello to her.
Keberatan kalau aku ikut? Aku ingin menyapanya.
Why didn't you answer my calls, Mom? I was so worried.
Kenapa Ibu tidak menjawab teleponku? Aku sangat khawatir.
You called me?
Kamu meneleponku?
See? You got missed calls from me, your daughter.
Lihat? Kamu dapat panggilan tak terjawab dariku, putrimu.
You're right.
Kamu benar.
My daughter's called me so many times.
Putriku meneleponku berkali-kali.
When you get a missed call next time, click this icon and call me back, okay?
Jika nanti ada panggilan tak terjawab, klik ikon ini dan telepon saya kembali, oke?
- Hmm.
- Hmm.
Hello, ma'am.
Halo, Bu.
Do you remember me?
Apakah kamu mengingatku?
Do you know Miyoung's friend Seokhee? I'm her older brother.
Kamu kenal Seokhee, teman Miyoung? Aku kakak laki-lakinya.
Don't you remember him? That's Seokcheol.
Kamu tidak ingat dia? Itu Seokcheol.
He used to visit your gimbap place often.
Dia sering mengunjungi tempat gimbapmu.
Yeah.
Ya.
You're Mr. Broom!
Anda Tuan Sapu!
Look at you all grown up!
Lihatlah kalian semua sudah tumbuh dewasa!
Mom, his name is Seokcheol, not Broom.
Bu, namanya Seokcheol, bukan Broom.
- You don't call someone a broom. - Oh!
- Anda tidak memanggil seseorang dengan sapu. - Oh!
Ma'am, you're right. I am Mr. Broom!
Nyonya, Anda benar. Saya Tuan Broom!
I used to hang around your store hoping to see Miyoung,
Aku dulu sering nongkrong di tokomu berharap bisa melihat Miyoung,
and you'd chase me away with a broom.
dan kau akan mengusirku dengan sapu.
Really?
Benar-benar?
- Yeah. - Are you serious?
- Ya. - Kamu serius?
Ma'am, your memory is great.
Nyonya, ingatan Anda hebat sekali.
Really.
Benar-benar.
No, Mom, I'm sorry.
Tidak, Bu, maafkan aku.
I can't take you home with me today, I'm sorry.
Aku tidak bisa mengantarmu pulang hari ini, maaf.
But I want to go home, Miyoung.
Tapi aku ingin pulang, Miyoung.
I know, I'd like that too.
Aku tahu, aku juga menginginkannya.
But I can't leave you there alone when I go to work.
Tapi aku tidak bisa meninggalkanmu sendirian di sana saat aku pergi bekerja.
What if you get lost again like that day?
Bagaimana jika Anda tersesat lagi seperti hari itu?
I don't care. I don't want to stay here.
Aku tidak peduli. Aku tidak mau tinggal di sini.
Hang in there, okay?
Bertahanlah, oke?
I'll work really hard and take you home soon.
Aku akan bekerja keras dan segera mengantarmu pulang.
Just a little longer.
Sedikit lebih lama.
Just a little longer, I'm sorry. Please hang in there.
Mohon bersabar sedikit lagi, maaf. Semoga kalian tetap bertahan.
I'm sorry.
Saya minta maaf.
I'm sorry, okay? I really am.
Maaf, oke? Sungguh.
ORTHOPEDIC CENTER
PUSAT ORTOPEDI
- Go on ahead. I'll catch up with you. - Shall I order for you?
Silakan saja. Aku akan menyusulmu. - Mau aku pesankan makanan untukmu?
- An iced Americano, please. - Okay.
- Tolong, Americano dingin. - Oke.
- I have an appointment today. - May I have your name, please?
- Saya ada janji hari ini. - Bolehkah saya tahu nama Anda?
- Go Jeongnim. - Pardon me?
- Go Jeongnim. - Maaf?
Go Jeongnim.
Go Jeongnim.
"Go Jeongnim."
"Go Jeongnim."
It has to be her.
Itu harus dia.
Seokkyung's friend.
Teman Seokkyung.
- Take good care of her. - Sure.
- Jaga dia baik-baik. - Tentu.
Mom, I have to go now.
Ibu, aku harus pergi sekarang.
Clap your hands.
Tepuk tanganmu.
- Come back soon. - I will. You take care.
- Segera kembali. - Aku akan kembali. Jaga dirimu.
I'll come see you too, ma'am.
Saya akan datang menemui Anda juga, Bu.
Did you hear him?
Apakah kamu mendengarnya?
Bye, Mom. I'll see you soon.
Sampai jumpa, Bu. Sampai jumpa lagi.
Bye, Mom.
Selamat tinggal, Ibu.
Bye.
Selamat tinggal.
Thanks... Mr. Broom.
Terima kasih... Tuan Broom.
Miyoung.
Miyoung.
- Let's go. - Where?
- Ayo pergi. - Ke mana?
- Let's sing. - What?
- Ayo bernyanyi. - Apa?
Come with me.
Mari ikut saya.
Why?
Mengapa?
SARANGBANG PROGRAM ROOM
SARANGBANG PROGRAM ROOM
Hello, dear elders.
Halo, para tetua yang terhormat.
May I have your attention, please?
Bolehkah saya minta perhatian Anda?
Seokcheol, I really can't do it.
Seokcheol, aku sungguh tidak bisa melakukannya.
It's okay, Miyoung.
Tidak apa-apa, Miyoung.
Look at them, they don't care about us.
Lihatlah mereka, mereka tidak peduli pada kita.
All right, everyone. Listen up...
Baiklah, semuanya. Dengarkan...
Okay, let's say you're paying attention.
Baiklah, anggap saja Anda memperhatikan.
Yes. Thank you, ma'am.
Ya. Terima kasih, Bu.
We've got a special program for you today.
Kami punya program khusus untuk Anda hari ini.
We've invited someone over...
Kami telah mengundang seseorang...
who is soon going to be a famous singer in this country.
yang akan segera menjadi penyanyi terkenal di negara ini.
Let's give her a warm welcome.
Mari kita sambut dia dengan hangat.
Ms. Kang Miyoung!
Ms. Kang Miyoung!
A round of applause for her!
Tepuk tangan untuknya!
Applause, please.
Tolong tepuk tangan.
I really can't sing in front of so many people.
Saya benar-benar tidak bisa bernyanyi di depan banyak orang.
Miyoung, imagine you're singing just for me.
Miyoung, bayangkan kamu bernyanyi hanya untukku.
Give it a shot, okay?
Cobalah, oke?
That's insane. Hey, film it.
Gila banget. Hei, rekam aja.
♪ I'll write you a letter ♪
??? Aku akan menulis surat untukmu???
♪ And tell you everything about how I feel ♪
??? Dan menceritakan segalanya tentang apa yang aku rasakan ???
♪ I will write to you ♪
??? Aku akan menulis kepadamu???
♪ About my unchanging heart ♪
??? Tentang hatiku yang tak berubah???
♪ I wished upon a star ♪
??? Aku berharap pada sebuah bintang ???
♪ I bet everything I had ♪
??? Aku pertaruhkan semua yang aku punya???
♪ That I'd show you ♪
??? Itu yang akan aku tunjukkan padamu???
♪ How endless my love for you is ♪
??? Betapa tak berujungnya cintaku padamu???
♪ I feel lonelier ♪
??? Aku merasa lebih kesepian???
♪ When I hug you like this ♪
??? Saat aku memelukmu seperti ini ???
♪ When I hold you in my dreams ♪
??? Saat aku memelukmu dalam mimpiku ???
♪ Wake me up ♪
??? Bangunkan aku ???
♪ I miss you so much ♪
??? Aku sangat merindukanmu ???
♪ I want to cry... ♪
??? Aku ingin menangis...???
Do you see this here?
Apakah Anda melihat ini di sini?
Do you see how narrow it is compared to the others?
Apakah Anda melihat betapa sempitnya dibandingkan dengan yang lain?
The fluid is sticking to this fibrous ring here.
Cairan tersebut menempel pada cincin berserat di sini.
It must be quite painful.
Pasti sangat menyakitkan.
- Do you have trouble walking? - Yes.
- Apakah Anda kesulitan berjalan? - Ya.
- I'll get a wheelchair for you. - Mmm-hmm.
- Aku akan ambilkan kursi roda untukmu. - Mmm-hmm.
Do you have to bend down or stay seated for a long time at work?
Apakah Anda harus membungkuk atau duduk dalam waktu lama saat bekerja?
Well...
Dengan baik...
I wouldn't call it work.
Saya tidak akan menyebutnya pekerjaan.
But, yeah, I guess you could say that.
Tapi, ya, saya rasa Anda bisa mengatakannya.
Don't you often sit cross-legged on the floor?
Bukankah Anda sering duduk bersila di lantai?
I bet you even bend down and look at something like this.
Saya yakin Anda bahkan membungkuk dan melihat sesuatu seperti ini.
How do you know?
Bagaimana kamu tahu?
- Jeongnim, don't you remember me? - Who...
- Jeongnim, kamu tidak mengingatku? - Siapa...
- Who is she? - It's Seokhee.
- Siapa dia? - Itu Seokhee.
Seokkyung's younger sister.
Adik perempuan Seokkyung.
- You really don't remember me? - Do you know her?
- Kamu betul-betul tidak mengingatku? - Kamu kenal dia?
She's my sister's high school friend.
Dia teman SMA saudara perempuanku.
- They're best friends. - Oh, really?
Mereka sahabat. - Oh, benarkah?
Oh, Seokhee. Yes, I remember you.
Oh, Seokhee. Ya, aku ingat kamu.
Easy, easy, easy!
Mudah, mudah, mudah!
Be careful!
Hati-hati!
I bet you're a terrible driver too.
Aku yakin kamu juga seorang pengemudi yang buruk.
Do you know this saying:
Tahukah Anda pepatah ini:
"You encounter your enemy's friend at the worst place and time"?
"Anda bertemu teman musuh Anda di tempat dan waktu terburuk"?
You just made that up, didn't you?
Anda hanya mengarangnya, bukan?
What's all this about "an enemy's friend"?
Apa maksudnya "teman musuh"?
Seokkyung ran away from home, so she's my enemy.
Seokkyung kabur dari rumah, jadi dia musuhku.
And you're her friend.
Dan kau temannya.
Where is she?
Dimana dia?
I have no idea where she is.
Saya tidak tahu di mana dia.
I know you do.
Aku tahu.
You two are always getting into trouble together.
Kalian berdua selalu mendapat masalah bersama.
Do you really have to be so mean to me?
Apakah kau benar-benar harus bersikap jahat padaku?
We haven't seen each other in such a long time.
Sudah lama kita tidak bertemu .
You think I'm mean?
Kau pikir aku jahat?
You remember my brother, the hot-tempered thug?
Kamu ingat saudaraku, si penjahat pemarah?
Want me to call him?
Ingin aku meneleponnya?
Then tell me where Park Seokkyung is.
Kalau begitu beritahu aku di mana Park Seokkyung.
- Is this it? - Yes, up there.
- Hanya inikah? - Ya, di sana.
Oh, okay.
Oh, oke.
Thanks for today.
Terima kasih untuk hari ini.
Don't mention it.
Jangan sebutkan itu.
Get home safe. I'll call you soon.
Sampai rumah dengan selamat. Aku akan segera meneleponmu.
Okay. Go on inside.
Oke. Silakan masuk.
Bye.
Selamat tinggal.
SEOKHEE
SEOKHEE
Yeah, what is it?
Ya, apa itu?
What the...
Apa-apaan...
Why are you laughing?
Mengapa kamu tertawa?
You remember Seokkyung's friend, Jeongnim?
Kau ingat teman Seokkyung, Jeongnim?
Jeongnim...
Jeongnim...
Ah, yes, the gambler.
Ah, ya, si penjudi.
Always came over to play cards at Seokkyung's hair salon.
Selalu datang untuk bermain kartu di salon rambut Seokkyung.
Yeah. She came to the hospital today. She's been admitted for a herniated disc.
Ya. Dia datang ke rumah sakit hari ini. Dia dirawat karena hernia diskus.
- Really? - Yes.
- Benarkah? - Ya.
I intimidated her into telling me where Seokkyung is.
Aku mengintimidasi dia agar memberitahuku di mana Seokkyung berada.
Where are you? I'm coming over.
Kamu di mana? Aku ke sana.
Got it.
Mengerti.
I'll be there soon.
Saya akan segera ke sana.
- Let's go! - What's her current location?
- Ayo pergi! - Di mana lokasinya saat ini?
It's on the app. Follow the map.
Ada di aplikasi. Ikuti peta.
- Okay. - Let's go.
- Baiklah. - Ayo pergi.
Are you sure it's safe for us to go by ourselves?
Apakah kamu yakin aman bagi kita untuk pergi sendiri?
There might be scary people at that gambling place.
Mungkin ada orang-orang menakutkan di tempat perjudian itu.
You still have that baseball bat in the trunk?
Anda masih menyimpan tongkat baseball di bagasi?
What exactly are you going to do with it?
Apa sebenarnya yang akan Anda lakukan dengannya?
Don't try to be clever. Just stay put, and I'll take care of it.
Jangan sok pintar. Diam saja, biar aku yang urus.
On some days it's good to have a thug for a brother.
Pada hari-hari tertentu, ada baiknya kita memiliki seorang preman sebagai saudara.
Sure, go ahead and take advantage of it.
Tentu saja, lanjutkan saja dan manfaatkan itu.
That must be it.
Pasti itu dia.
It might seem like a club, but it's actually a gambling house.
Kelihatannya seperti klub, tapi sebenarnya itu adalah rumah judi.
There should be a guard in a car somewhere.
Seharusnya ada penjaga di dalam mobil di suatu tempat.
Over there. I think that's him.
Di sana. Kurasa itu dia.
I think there'll be thugs inside the place too.
Aku pikir akan ada penjahat di tempat itu juga.
Let's go in.
Ayo masuk.
You're not going anywhere. It's dangerous.
Kamu tidak akan ke mana-mana. Itu berbahaya.
Then what do we do?
Lalu apa yang harus kita lakukan?
Try to lure that guard out of his car.
Cobalah untuk memancing penjaga itu keluar dari mobilnya.
Think you can do it?
Apakah Anda merasa mampu melakukannya?
Okay.
Oke.
Be careful. Don't do anything more than that.
Hati-hati. Jangan lakukan lebih dari itu.
Yeah, okay.
Ya, oke.
What do you want?
Apa yang kamu inginkan?
I came to gamble.
Saya datang untuk berjudi.
Gamble?
Berjudi?
How did you find this place?
Bagaimana Anda menemukan tempat ini?
- Jeongnim told me about it. - Oh.
- Jeongnim yang menceritakannya padaku. - Oh.
Where is she? Are you here alone?
Di mana dia? Kamu sendirian di sini?
Uh, she told me to go inside and wait for her.
Eh, dia menyuruhku masuk dan menunggunya.
You must be eager to get in.
Anda pasti bersemangat untuk masuk.
I got you.
Aku mengerti kamu.
Just a sec.
Tunggu sebentar.
All right. We have a customer coming in. Do you copy?
Baiklah. Ada pelanggan yang datang. Bisa dengar?
All right.
Baiklah.
Come on in.
Silakan masuk.
Tell them it's two customers.
Beritahu mereka kalau ada dua pelanggan.
All right, ladies and gentlemen. You heard the cuckoo.
Baiklah, hadirin sekalian. Anda sudah dengar bunyi kukuknya.
Time to hand over my commission. Have two chips ready, please.
Saatnya menyerahkan komisi saya. Tolong siapkan dua chip.
Get rich.
Menjadi kaya.
Could you get us a new ashtray?
Bisakah Anda memberi kami asbak baru?
Here's a tip for you.
Berikut kiat untuk Anda.
My gosh. Thank you so much.
Ya ampun. Terima kasih banyak.
Mr. Hwang, I bet Lady Luck will be on your side.
Tuan Hwang, saya yakin Dewi Fortuna akan berpihak pada Anda.
What a generous man you are.
Anda sungguh pria yang murah hati.
- Here, have a tip from me too. - Gee, thank you.
- Ini, ada tip dariku juga. - Wah, terima kasih.
Two each, please.
Dua untuk masing-masingnya, silakan.
I'm sorry. Please continue. Sorry.
Maaf. Silakan lanjutkan. Maaf.
Seokkyung.
Seokkyung.
What's going on?
Apa yang sedang terjadi?
Seokhee.
Seokhee.
Seokcheol.
Seokcheol.
Long time no see.
Lama tak jumpa.
- Yeah. - How could you hide in a place like this?
- Ya. - Bagaimana kau bisa bersembunyi di tempat seperti ini?
- Let's go. This is embarrassing. - Go where?
Ayo pergi. Ini memalukan. - Mau ke mana?
- Come on. It's embarrassing. - How did you know I was here?
Ayolah. Memalukan sekali. - Bagaimana kau tahu aku di sini?
- That's not important. Come on. - Let go of my arm, Seokhee.
- Itu tidak penting. Ayo. - Lepaskan lenganku, Seokhee.
Wait, let's talk...
Tunggu, mari kita bicara...
- Sorry. - Are you kidding me?
- Maaf. - Kamu bercanda?
Ashtray seems to have loan sharks chasing her again.
Ashtray tampaknya diburu rentenir lagi.
Seems like it.
Sepertinya begitu.
I told you to come along quietly. Get up. Let's go.
Sudah kubilang, ikutlah diam-diam. Bangun. Ayo pergi.
Seokcheol, wait.
Seokcheol, tunggu.
Let's go. Are you okay?
Ayo pergi. Kamu baik-baik saja?
- I'm fine. - Hurry up.
- Aku baik-baik saja. - Cepatlah.
Who are you, mister?
Siapa Anda, Tuan?
I'm her brother. I came to take her home.
Aku kakaknya. Aku datang untuk menjemputnya pulang.
What are you saying, punk?
Apa yang kau katakan, berandalan?
Obong, please don't. You don't want any trouble, believe me.
Obong, jangan. Kamu nggak mau ada masalah, percayalah.
He's my little brother.
Dia adik laki-lakiku.
Seokcheol, don't do anything, or I'll get mad!
Seokcheol, jangan lakukan apa pun, atau aku akan marah!
- Okay? - Okay.
Oke? - Oke.
Ashtray.
Asbak.
Are they really your little brother and sister?
Apakah mereka benar-benar adik laki-laki dan perempuanmu?
Yes, ma'am.
Ya, Bu.
- Hey, lady. - Hey.
- Hei, nona. - Hei.
- Don't call her "Ashtray." - Calm down.
- Jangan panggil dia "Asbak." - Tenang saja.
Where are your manners?
Dimana sopan santunmu?
Don't disrespect me. I'll beat you up.
Jangan tidak hormat padaku. Aku akan menghajarmu.
- No. - No, ma'am.
- Tidak. - Tidak, Bu.
They're my little siblings. They don't know any better.
Mereka adik-adikku. Mereka tidak tahu apa-apa.
Seokhee, my name is Ashtray now.
Seokhee, namaku sekarang Ashtray.
- They're my siblings, ma'am. - Get out of my way!
- Mereka saudara-saudaraku, Bu. - Minggir!
How dare you push my sister!
Beraninya kau mendorong adikku!
Seokhee!
Seokhee!
- Ah! - Brat!
- Ah! - Anak nakal!
You nasty little--
Kamu anak kecil yang jahat--
You people don't know who you're messing with.
Kalian tidak tahu dengan siapa kalian bermain-main.
- Kill her! - Rip her to shreds!
- Bunuh dia! - Robek dia sampai hancur!
Hey, stop, stop!
Hei, berhenti, berhenti!
It hurts!
Sakit!
Seokhee!
Seokhee!
Seokkyung!
Seokkyung!